[suspenseful music]
[as Master Wu]
Focus your Spinjitzu, Arin.
Yes, Master Wu.
[Arin yelling and grunting]
Aw, did that hurt, "Ninja nerd"?
I thought Ninja are
supposed to be tough.
Oh, wait, maybe it's because
you're not a Ninja, loser.
Careful.
I-I'm fully trained... well,
partially fully trained,
but my mom says I'm
getting way good.
[laughs] Who trained you?
Mr. Mop Master here?
-[Arin grunting]
-Who cares about Ninja anyway?
Just a bunch of
babies in pajamas.
You better not be
making fun of the Ninja.
[dramatic music]
This has nothing to do
with you, Snake Boy.
The Ninja don't sit back when
someone's getting bullied,
and neither do I.
[dramatic music]
[Frak hissing]
I probably could
have handled them,
but thanks for the help.
I'm Arin, by the way.
Name's Frak.
You, uh, make that yourself?
Yeah, kind of dorky, right?
Better than mine.
I made it outta my
uncle's shed skin,
which is kind of gross, I guess,
but I love Master Wu
and the Ninja.
Oh, no way!
Ninja, go!
Lloyd is my favorite,
though I did get a
Zane haircut once.
I've always been a Cole guy.
[imitating blast-off]
My dream is to get an Elemental
Power, just like the Ninja.
Oh, wouldn't that be the best?
I'm trying to learn
Spinjitzu on my own
and it's going great,
but also it's going awful.
My parents keep telling me
it's only a matter of time
before I'll do a perfect
Spinjitzu tornado.
Oh, I'll practice with you.
[uplifting music]
Arin, what are you doing here?
Right now, being hauled
off by security bots.
I'm here with my master
and these are my guests.
[robot chattering]
[dramatic music]
You're competing in the
Tournament of the Sources?
That's right.
You're looking at the
Elemental Master of Quake!
[earthquake rumbling]
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[fire rumbling]
[earthquake rumbling]
You have Elemental Powers now?
How?
Your mom or dad weren't
masters, were they?
Nope, I was just a regular kid.
But then the Merge
happened, and boom,
I could cause things to shake.
The first time was so freaky.
I burst a sewer pipe,
which led to a kind of
involved cleanup process
that's probably best
we don't talk about.
[dragon chattering]
But then I found a master
who trained me
to use my powers properly.
Why are you here?
You're not gonna
believe this, but--
Arin, Riyu, there you are.
We were so worried.
You're here with the Ninja?
I told you
you wouldn't believe it.
Hey, everyone.
This is my old friend, Frak.
You mean Frak Frak?
Like the guy who taught
you how to make pies?
If that's true,
we have to thank you.
I'm normally a cake guy,
but even I have to admit,
Arin's pies are the best.
The Cole likes my
pie recipes? [laughs]
It's okay, Frak.
You wanna come hang out with us?
Oh, are you serious?
-I...
-[phone buzzing]
Oh, wait, my master just
sent a training alert.
He does not like
anyone to be late.
I gotta run.
I'll find you later, Arin.
It's so amazing to meet you all.
Pleasure to meet you too, Frak.
Nya knows my name.
[stunned shiver]
Arin, we're now officially
invited to the games,
so we're getting a tour.
This is Roby, Master
of Ceremonies,
and his Uncle Bleckt,
the Minister of Ledgering.
Did I get that right?
-Welcome to the--
-Try Minister of Boring.
Ha, I kid, we're family.
He loves it, now come on.
Behold, Foundation Street,
the traditional
center of the city.
[crowd applauding]
This tour is a chance
to keep an eye out
for anyone suspicious.
Remember the real
reason we're here,
to find out who
killed the Matriarch.
On it.
Using my keen detective skills.
[Bleckt] Observe the arrangement
of architectural
features as the--
Arrangement of blah, blah, blah.
Sorry, Uncle, but is your plan
to put the Ninja to sleep?
The City of Temples must be
treated with reverent respect.
Forget the old rules, Uncs.
It's a new era.
The realms are merged.
These are the first
games where I'm in charge
and tradition is out.
It's time for disruption.
Ninja, saddle up.
I'm about to show you the
tightest thing in the city.
Check it, seven-headed dragon!
[makes animated noises]
Sweet, right?
Yes, all the yeses!
[giggling]
See, she gets it.
She's clearly the smartest one.
I have no record of
a seven-headed dragon
in the history of any realm
with which I am acquainted.
That's 'cause it's not real.
It's interpretive
art representing
the Seven Source Dragons of
myth, if you believe in that.
But it's also awesome,
and it's been here,
like, a million years,
so it's almost as
old as Uncle Bleckt. [cackles]
[laughing]
Anyhow,
like the fairy tale goes,
all Elemental Powers come
from the Source Dragons.
Is not a fairy tale, Roby.
Whatever. The games were
created forever ago
to celebrate the gifts
of the "Source Dragons."
So Elemental Masters
are called to compete.
It's pretty much a celebration
of your awesomeness.
What does the winner get?
Whoa, we gotta talk rules first.
When someone loses a match,
they give their power
to this Elemental Cup,
and with it, I give their
powers to the winner,
who then has both powers.
Am I right?
This goes on as each
competitor that wins
gains more and more
powers to compete with.
The winner ends up with
everyone's Elemental Powers.
The champion then
returns the Elements
to their rightful Masters
in a victory ceremony
that commemorates
the Source Dragons
allowing mortals to be
given Elemental Powers.
Victory ceremonies are boring.
Ours will be an extreme
victory extravaganza.
Doesn't that seem super risky?
Yeah, what if the
winner is evil?
They'd have everyone's powers.
They could go rogue and take
over the world or something.
Stop stressing.
Nothing like that's ever
happened, and it couldn't.
The Elemental Cup's
like a safety switch.
Someone tries something stupid,
I just pull the powers
back into the Cup,
and only the Games Master, me,
knows the secrets of
how to use this cup.
Lloyd, Arin, what a pleasure
it is to see you old chums.
Zant-Tanz? No way!
This is the guy Arin
and I told you about,
leader of the Mother Garden.
You're an Elemental Master?
Why didn't you tell us?
I didn't even know
until I got invited
to this delightful
convivial convention.
-What's your power?
-Plants.
Witness a whimsical
demonstration.
[air whooshing]
[stones cracking]
[dramatic music]
[laughs] Flower shower.
-Cool.
-Huh, cool.
Oh, I am such a
sucker for whimsy.
Wow.
And you didn't know you
were an Elemental Master?
I just thought I was
very good at gardening.
And I have splendid
news for your tummies.
I'll be bringing my extra
sweet Mucoid Berries
to tonight's banquet.
-Banquet?
-Yep.
Pre-tournament festivities
include dining and delights,
and you're invited, of course.
You'll meet some of
your competitors.
[soft meditative music]
Ooh.
Oh.
[creature belching]
Ah, here's my favorite team.
Of course, don't tell
anyone else I said that.
There's a full buffet,
but also take a menu.
You can order anything
your heart desires.
Come on, let me show you
around this epic banquet.
Tox, is that you?
Like the hair.
Mr. Pale, so good to see you,
uh, not see you. [laughs]
[gasps] You!
You disappeared
after the Blood Moon.
-Where'd you--
-[grunts] Help me, Ana.
Huh?
[bones cracking]
Uh, Jordana?
I was wondering where
you got off to, Jordana.
[suspenseful music]
I was never far, Nokt.
Look who we have here.
-[Wyldfyre snarling]
-You brought the whole gang?
Hey, didn't you have two
red Ninjas in your group?
I can't remember.
This is for Kai.
Eat fire!
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
No fighting outside the arena.
-Big-time rule.
-But I gotta mess this guy up.
Love that energy.
Love it.
But save it for the games,
or else, sad face,
you'll be expelled.
Don't blame me.
Just how it is.
Roby's right.
Don't let your anger
get the best of you.
We'll have a chance
to beat them.
[sighs] Okay.
I won't fight.
Want to, but won't.
[dramatic music]
What's wrong, Sora?
Not sure.
Something strange just happened.
[mysterious music]
Wha--
Hey, you're a devonian, right?
I've never actually...
Nice to meet you, too.
Ah!
-Did I startle you, Lloyd?
-Ras.
If you've come to fight...
We've all come to fight.
My team's here to
win the tournament
-and honor the Source Dragons.
-[bell ringing]
[Roby] Ting-ting, ding-ding,
ding-ding, ting-ting.
Hi, hi.
Attention, Masters.
One night before the New
Tournament of the Sources,
I am reminded of what
the Cragling poet,
Rockworth, once said.
[growling, rock-grinding noises]
I have been betrayed
for the last time.
[guests gasping]
Empress Beatrix?
[robots chattering]
We've beaten you once,
Empress, and we'll do it again.
Empress?
[chuckles] So you must be the
Ninja who dethroned my sister.
You had no right.
I spent years plotting
my revenge on my twin,
and you stole that from me.
Twin?
-You're--
-Zeatrix!
Yeah, don't love
you storming in.
All your sloppy drama's
messing up my big speech.
A banquet to which the
Elemental Master of Shockwave
was not invited is
a grave act of betrayal
-I will not forgive.
-Ugh.
Everything with you is
grave act to betrayal this,
a pox upon your house that.
I'm sure not inviting you
was just an oversight,
right, Uncle Bleckt?
[suspenseful music]
Oversight?
I still haven't been
assigned quarters
like every other competitor,
and now I'm excluded
from the welcome banquet?
I know what you're doing.
You're sidelining
me because you know
I'm destined to destroy
every single one of these
so-called masters in the games.
-[laughs] All right.
-[laughs] Yeah, right.
Your sister didn't find you
so difficult to defeat.
-[gasps]
-Ras! [snarls]
What are you doing here?
You're no Elemental Master.
I command Elemental Masters.
I know you conspired
with my sister
to take my father's life.
I look forward to you
meeting the same fate.
[Ras growling]
Roby, any more oversights,
and you will pay, personally.
Zeatrix, Elemental Master
of Buzzkill, am I right?
Dude, my speech
was gonna be epic.
But the moment's gone.
Everyone eat, eat.
Game's tomorrow, whatever.
[Nya] I've been to some
awkward dinners,
like when Jay ate
the host's fern
thinking it was a side salad.
Or when Jay asked for
sushi from a fish waiter
in the undersea
kingdom of Merlopia.
Actually, being with Jay
led to many awkward dinners.
But tonight was in the top ten.
I thought I was seeing
Beatrix in my visions
this whole time.
But was it Zeatrix?
What could it mean?
Maybe it means she's the
one who killed the Matriarch
and took her horns.
What makes you think that?
We know the horns are
a source of power.
What if she plans to use them
somehow to win the games?
She seemed pretty
confident she'd win,
like she knows something
that the rest of us don't.
It's gotta be Ras.
He's attacked the
Matriarch before,
and he captured a Source Dragon.
And Ras did the whole
Blood Moon thing
because he wanted to bring
back the Forbidden Five.
What if it was for these games?
And when he didn't get all five,
maybe he needed the
horns as a backup plan.
The winner does get
everyone's Elemental Powers.
That kind of thing
smells like a Ras plan
and ties it all to
the Source Dragons.
Crazy dinner.
But it's obvious who
the dragon killer is.
Right, Ras.
Or Zeatrix.
What?
No, it's definitely Bleckt.
The stuffy ledger guy?
You've seen how he
treats the amazing Roby.
[scoffs] Jealous much?
"The amazing Roby"?
All of these theories
are worth considering,
but we do not have enough
data to reach a conclusion.
Zane's right, we
need to know more.
Rest up.
The games start tomorrow.
[mysterious music]
[dragon yawning]
[sighs]
[crickets chirping]
[Ninjas snoring]
[suspenseful music]
[dragon grumbling]
[dragon roaring]
What's going on?
[Zane] It is an armed intruder.
Detecting high
levels of hostility.
You tried to Ninja into
a room full of Ninja?
Not smart, buddy.
[dragon roaring]
[dramatic music]
[powers rumbling]
[window crashing]
No one sneaks into--
Hey! [grunts]
[dragon roaring]
I was actually getting a good
night's sleep for a change.
Thanks for ruining that.
[air whooshing]
Who are you?
Did Ras send you?
[air whooshing]
[grunting]
Oh, we're not done talking.
[wood crashing]
[grunting]
[dramatic music]
[dogs bark]
[sighs]
Stop.
You are disturbing the peace.
Conflict is only allowed
during the games.
Lloyd, is that you?
What's all this
hubbub and commotion?
Whoever this is
just tried to give me
an early wake-up call with this.
-[crowd gasping]
-It is true.
We are all witnesses.
Who is it, Lloyd?
Let's find out.
A bot?
[electricity crackling]
That's definitely not
one of our security bots,
I can tell you that.
Whatever it is, I have
a pretty good guess
about who sent it.
Do you? Maybe it's the same
person who sent one after me.
[bot crashing]
And a third
attacker, it appears.
The damage is too extensive
to access its mechanical memory.
Then how can we
know who sent them?
Tox, you're the Elemental
Master of Poison.
What do you make of this?
Hmm, no question.
That's a rare Gelba thorn
from the Sevateam plant.
Never heard of it.
Where are they from?
Only one place in all the
Merged Lands, the Mother Garden.
But the Mother
Garden's protected.
You can't take
plants outta there
without the permission
of its leader.
Well, yes, I am the general
of the Mucoid Warriors
and supreme leader
of the Mother Garden,
but I assure you, I've got
nothing to do with this.
Although, Tox is correct about
the origin of the Gelba thorns.
They can only come from my home.
[crowd gasping]
Zant-Tanz is our friend.
I'm sure he didn't do this.
He is not my friend.
The thorns prove
it can only be him.
And attacking fellow
competitors is penalized
with immediate exile.
I'm telling you, there's
no way Zant-Tanz--
I want him gone.
[crowd muttering]
Looks like you're
not the only one.
But it's not fair.
Lloyd, it's okay.
I'm innocent.
But if my leaving
would comfort people,
I will exile myself voluntarily.
I do have some rock-stacking
to do at home.
However, be warned,
I did not do this.
Whoever sent these attacker
bots is still among you.
Sure, sure, whatever.
[fingers snapping]
Enough excitement for one night.
Get some rest, everyone.
First competitions are tomorrow!
Huh?
Jay?
Jay!
[mysterious music]
[closing theme music plays]